魂斗羅 -> gryZor -> Contra

^that basically explains it.

- WHAT EXACTLY HAS BEEN HACKED? -

Text. In fact, nothing BUT text has been edited besides the title screen.

- HOW TO USE AN IPS FILE? -

!!! Apply to the Japanese version of Contra [Contra (J)] It may be mislabeled as Gryzor (J)!!!

a) use Lunar IPS
b) use Nintendulator
c) ask someone on a ROMHACKING NET forum or NESDEV site

...if you still can't figure out how:

d) Google "IPS Patch" & go from there

e) find a whole bunch of aluminum foil, wad it up, & put it in you microwave; then set it to "HIGH" for 5 minutes
f) swallow a whole bunch of Altoids & chug a bottle of Coke

- VERSION -

1.1: fixed a "glitch" that "ruined" the "gameplay"

Thanks to:

-Eddie Collazo for letting us have many of his NES games, including Contra :)
-Manuel Dillinger for providing accurate translation, whether I was able to use it or not. :/
-RHDN member known as "Pennywise" for giving me competition :D
-Konami Kukeiha Club for creating awesome music to listen to while testing this game through

	-James "QuestMaster" 11/Something/2009