
            Woody Poko (うっでいぽこ)
    NES/Famicom translation patch v 1.00
              1/14/09 sqpat
        http://www.sqpat.com/trans


-----------------------------
Disclaimer-------------------
-----------------------------

This is a fan translation project. This project is not 
affiliated with Nintendo or dB-Soft. This translation
is not for sale and was not made for profit.

-----------------------------
Patching---------------------
-----------------------------

Apply the included .IPS patch to a Woody Poko NES/famicom
ROM image using Snes-Tool or some other IPS patching tool.

-----------------------------
Woody Poko-------------------
-----------------------------

    This game is an early famicom title (1987) made by 
dB-SOFT, who I've never heard of. It's an adventure game 
with platforming and RPG elements. You collect items and
money, go to shops, get information, and progress through
four or five levels.

    That said, the game is a little confusing. The hints
are sometimes vague, and you're sometimes expected to find
hidden holes which only appear if you walk over them.
The control doesn't always make sense. For example, when
you first go to a shop, you might end up stealing an item
by accident and being branded a thief for the rest of the 
game. Unless you are in one of the last levels, being
branded a thief pretty much spells the end of your quest
since you can't really use the shops anymore.

    Overall the game is pretty mediocre. You can have fun
with it, and it was probably a good game when it was 
released, considering it's era.

-----------------------------
Gameplay Issues--------------
-----------------------------

    I don't think there are any problems in the gameplay
stemming from the translation hack itself.

-----------------------------
Translation Commentary-------
-----------------------------

    First of all, the game had only a hiragana alphabet,
so besides the normal obstacles in translating an NES game
lacking kanji, the script was now even more confusing than
usual.

    There were a few lines that i wasn't happy with, but
they did not come up in game, so I really don't know how
to gather the context to better translate them.

    There was a series of dialogue mentioning ingredients
for some kind of recipe that involved fetching one or two
things. I couldn't find this in the game, and it mentioned
getting a bee, which i didn't find in the game, either.
Pointers exist for this text in the ROM, but I don't know
whether it's ever actually used.

    If a lot of the "hints" you pay and trade items for
seem useless or confusing, that's because they generally
are. The guy who asks for money seems particularly useless
in general, while the girl who asks for items is more hit
or miss.

    Speaking of that useless guy asking you for money all
the time, some of his lines were kind of confusing. I
don't know if they were puns or word plays or something.

    One other line i didnt understand was this one:

こびとの「はんんす」は なんかくれるってさ

I think it means 

"a dwarf said a 'hannsu' or something was coming." 

The intent seems to be to allude to something that sounds
like 'hannsu' in Japanese, but I'm completely in the dark.
I also don't know who the heck this dwarf is.

    The ending mentions an old man named Matsumura. Perhaps
the game's manual mentioned who this 'Matsumura' was, since
the name appears nowhere else in the entire script. I can
only assume that the old man refers to the guy Poko speaks
to in the first stage's opening dialogue.

    Speaking of that opening, it seemed Poko had awoke
from a nightmare involving wooden dolls. I wasn't sure
this would make very much sense, so I changed it to a 
Jason reference.

    And speaking of that ending, i have no idea what the
"Bunny Dance" is all about.

    This translation could probably use some work, since
it's my first translation hack and second script
translation. I hope for my Japanese to improve in the
future, so I might come back to it to make things better.
However, I think it's more than adequate as it stands.


-----------------------------
Tools Used-------------------
-----------------------------

FCEUXDSP
Hexposure
XVI32 hex editor
Paint
Tile Layer Pro
yy-chr
Cartographer
Atlas
Notepad
Wordpad
NJStar
http://www.jisho.org

-----------------------------
Special Thanks---------------
-----------------------------

GilGalad - helping me with a lot of general questions 
regarding ROM translations, and for helping me with 
utilities.

SliverX - helping me with some PPU hacking/debugging

#arc-nova.org on DarkMyst.org - Pretty much the only ROM
hacking related community i frequent.

