SNOOPY'S ERRAND ADVENTURES
Hacked by Zynk Oxhyde
2016

--------------
Date Released:
--------------
v1.0 May 13, 2016

------------
Description:
------------
This is an English translation of "Snoopy no Hajimete no Otsukai", a puzzle game for the Nintendo Gameboy.

------
Story:
------
Snoopy wants to play ball but Charlie Brown insisted that he do some errands first. So off Snoopy in his errand adventure!

---------------
Game Mechanics:
---------------
The game is a puzzle game. Before starting an errand, list down the items on the shopping list so you won't forget what you'd be buying; 
you only need to buy one item per shop. Then guide Snoopy using the arrows. Be very careful not letting him go off the road or get scrolled 
out or he'd die. Make sure he won't get distracted by clowns and other suspicious stuff on the way or you'll lose time and shopping item limit.
The game has 45 stages (or errands).

Controls:
A = Confirm
B = Cancel
Directional button = Left and Right to select commands for Snoopy; the footprint icon is the Stay icon
Start = Pause
Select = Quit

------
Items:
------
Charlie Brown	= prevents Snoopy from getting distracted
Hammer		= break obstacles
Fish		= cat bait
Net		= raccoon bait (not sure)
Roadblock	= stops running vehicles for a while (seen once)
Skateboard	= move faster and can jump over pits
Slingshot	= scare birds away
Trampoline	= jump over obstacles

---------------------------
Interactive objects on map:
---------------------------
Arrows		= pre-planted arrows forces Snoopy to walk to the direction its pointing to
Moving panel	= step on it to reach the other side
Sinkhole	= Snoopy falls in it, lose time to move
Stumps		= Snoopy sits on it, nothings lost other than time
Switch		= walk over it to switch the direction of conveyor belts 
Spring		= shoots Snoopy in a straight path; plant a Stay icon to stop
W-panel		= a warp, teleporting Snoopy to a specified area

----------
Obstacles:
----------
Beetle		= distracts Snoopy that makes him lose a shopping item limit. Pickup Charlie Brown to counter it
Bird		= moves items to a different location. Use a Slingshot to scare it away
Cat/Raccoon	= getting caught by it makes Snoopy lose a shopping item limit. Use a Fish/Net, respectively
Clown		= distracts Snoopy to lose precious time. Pickup Charlie Brown to counter it
Origami		= stepping on one makes Snoopy lose a shopping item limit. Pickup Charlie Brown to counter it

--------
Changes:
--------
v1.0 (05/13/2016) - initial release
Aside from translating the game into English, there are other things that are edited:
* edited the title screen
* the TOWN, HILL and DREAM errand screens
* the GOAL signs
* created a shop icon

---------
ZIP file:
---------
1. This readme
2. SNOOPY(EN).ips
3. SNOOPY-PASSWORDS.txt

----------------
ROM Information:
----------------
File:   Snoopy no Hajimete no Otsukai (J) [S][!].gb
Length: 131072 Bytes (1 Mbit)
CRC32:  8900A7C0
MD5:    4F597338 777CC0B6 7465BD0D DE285645
SHA1:   535A85E3 955EC587 54395A8B F7C4F5B7 D319E57F

--------
Credits:
--------
Zynk Oxhyde - Hacking, Translation, Title screen graphics

----------
Utilities:
----------
BRB Gameboy emulator & debugger by Bas Steendijk
WindHex hex editor by Bongo`
YY-CHR ROM graphics editor by YY

---------------
Special Thanks:
---------------
Romhacking.net - for hosting the patch

--------
Contact:
--------
Email: zynkoxhyde@yahoo.com

-----------
Disclaimer:
-----------
Zynk Oxhyde is not related/affiliated with Nintendo or Kemco in any way.
Kemco & Charles M. Schulz owns this game & characters all rights reserved, respectively.
This patch is not for profit! This patch is free! 
Don't distribute this in pre-patched ROMs!
Don't ask the author for ROMs. Get your ROMs from anyhow you like.