BRAVE FIGHTER OF THE SUN: FIGHBIRD
Hacked by Zynk Oxhyde
2016

--------------
Date Released:
--------------
v1.0 January 4, 2016

------------
Description:
------------
This is an English translation of "Taiyou no Yuusha Fighbird" for the NES.

------
Story:
------
From Wikipedia :P
In 2010, an evil energy being called Draias comes flying to the earth. It co-operates with Jango, a wicked scientist, 
in secret to bring ruin to the world. Upon its arrival, the Space Police Force put their spirits into special android 
machines built by Doctor Amano that have transformable bodies. Fighbird enters one such android and lives as the human 
Yutaro Katori. He transforms into the super robot Fighbird when the enemy attacks.

--------
Changes:
--------
v1.2 (01/16/2016)
* Minor font edits

v1.1 (01/06/2016)
* Retry & End screen garbled text fixed

v1.0 (01/04/2016) - initial release
Aside from translating the game into English, there are other things that are edited:
* A spiffy title screen
* That tiny "FIGHBIRD" logo
* Translated the stage titles
* Baron Team menu names
* Some portraits are fixed

---------
ZIP file:
---------
1. This readme
2. FIGHBIRD(EN).ips

----------------
ROM Information:
----------------
File:   Taiyou no Yuusha Firebird (Japan).nes
Length: 262160 Bytes (2 Mbit)
CRC32:  BE1D0344
MD5:    A52B0CFB DFF806F7 0F88A28A AD3017BF
SHA1:   848FAF41 EF0B9592 3DDB2ED7 ADF6063F 79FBE139

--------
Credits:
--------
Zynk Oxhyde - Full Hacking and Translation

----------
Utilities:
----------
WindHex hex editor by Bongo`
YY-CHR ROM graphics editor by YY
FCEUX NES emulator debuggers

---------------
Special Thanks:
---------------
Romhacking.net - for hosting the patch
reyvgm - for reporting garbled textx (why'd you get a gameover? JK)
(wraith) - for reporting ROM information

--------
Contact:
--------
Email: zynkoxhyde@yahoo.com

-----------
Disclaimer:
-----------
Zynk Oxhyde is not related/affiliated with Nintendo or Irem in any way.
Irem/Sunrise owns this game & characters all rights reserved.
This patch is not for profit! This patch is free! Don't distribute this in pre-patched ROMs!
Don't ask Zynk Oxhyde for ROMs. Get your ROMs from anyhow you like.