PERMAN: RETURN THE SPACE SAUCER!
Hacked by Zynk Oxhyde
2016

--------------
Date Released:
--------------
v2.0 March 2, 2016

------------
Description:
------------
This is an English translation of "Perman: Enban wo Torikaese" for the NES. The game is based on an anime of the same title.

------
Story:
------
Birdman's space saucer was stolen by Dr. Mad and its up to Perman to recover it and save the day.

---------------
Game Mechanics:
---------------
The game is a action platformer with a side of boardgame boss battle. The game has 7 stages.
Controls:
A = Jump; Jump on enemies will kill them
B = Attack; hold it during messages for quick skim
Left/Right = Move
Down = Crouch; You can move Left/Right while crouching
Start = Pause

------------
Field Items:
------------
POW	    = projectile attack that can break certain blocks; getting 2 of these will increase the range of the projectile
Fist	    = the same with POW but picking it up is equivalent to 2 POWs
Gun	    = turns enemies into animals
1UP	    = 1 extra life
Soft Cream  = restores 1 health
Pancakes    = fully restores health
P badge	    = used for the boardgame boss battle
Perman Mask = invincibility for a few seconds
Banana	    = spins around the player and damages foes, only when your're playing as Booby/Perman#2

-----------------
Mini-game prizes:
-----------------
You get to play some mini-games when entering a special door
You get 1UP or 3UP for winning the game with mistakes
You get special items for the boardgame if you win a perfect game without mistakes:
	Dice = a trick dice that gets you faces of 5 or 6
	Doll = a copy robot that doubles your max HP 

----------
Boardgame:
----------
The boss battle is a boardgame, roll a dice, move the no. of spaces the dice face has, land on tiles with symbols give a player some quirks:
Blank tile =attack rival with random damage point range
POW	   =gives rival strong damage
Soft cream =restores 1 HP
Pancakes   =restores more HP
?-symbol   =gives either 3 actions
		1. a pass/lose 1 turn
		2. move back rival
		3. get an extra turn
P-badge	   =call a teammate, each teammate has different effects set for each stage, effects are:
		1. weak damage to rival
		2. strong damage to rival
		3. HP recovery (Note: PM#2=banana; PM#3=cake; PM#4=taco(short for/or not for takoyaki)

--------
Changes:
--------
v2.0 (03/02/2016)
* New Title screen! A big THANK YOU to Proveaux!

v1.0 (02/26/2016) - initial release
Aside from translating the game into English, there are other things that are edited:
* A minor title screen edit (it seems the titlescreen is compressed) - (FIXED in v2.0)
* The "GOAL" on the boardgame
* Borders on the big score numbers and on the POW pickups

---------
ZIP file:
---------
1. This readme
2. PERMAN(EN).ips

----------------
ROM Information:
----------------
File:   Paaman - Enban wo Torikaese!! (J).nes
Length: 262160 Bytes (2 Mbit)
CRC32:  02DD2B01
MD5:    3AC89998 05C512AA 03CFA815 9D08B32F
SHA1:   B75325F4 29865AAF F7B8DCFF BE55D0A2 F7D44D75

-----
NOTE:
-----
The original game works on most emulators except for FCEUX 2.2.2.

--------
Credits:
--------
Zynk Oxhyde - Hacking, Translation, Title screen graphics
Proveaux - Title screen hacking

----------
Utilities:
----------
WindHex hex editor by Bongo`
YY-CHR ROM graphics editor by YY
FCE Ultra eXtended-Debug 1.0a by Bbitmaster & Parasyte

---------------
Special Thanks:
---------------
Romhacking.net - for hosting the patch

--------
Contact:
--------
Email: zynkoxhyde@yahoo.com

-----------
Disclaimer:
-----------
Zynk Oxhyde and Proveaux are not related/affiliated with Nintendo or Irem in any way.
Irem/Fujiko F. Fujio owns this game & characters all rights reserved.
This patch is not for profit! This patch is free! Don't distribute this in pre-patched ROMs!
Don't ask the author for ROMs. Get your ROMs from anyhow you like.