ADVENTURE ISLAND IV
Hacked by Zynk Oxhyde
2018

--------------
Date Released:
--------------
v1.0 July 14, 2018

------------
Description:
------------
This is a complete English translation of Takahashi Meijin no Bouken Jima IV for the NES.

There's an additional patch with extra graphical changes.

---------------
Game Mechanics:
---------------
Controls:
A = Jump
B = Attack; Enter door; Hold B to run faster when you get the D-coin; Hold UP to throw Boomerang up
UP = Climp ladders; Lay Warp Egg on a pedestal
DOWN = Decend ladders; Lay down; Move LEFT/RIGHT to crawl
Start = Menu
Select = Map

-----------
Menu Items:
-----------
WEAPON & ITEMS (get these from defeating bosses)
Bone		- default projectile weapon
Hammer		- melee weapon; key to next area; breaks stones
Torch		- melee weapon; light up dark areas
Water Gun	- projectile weapon; extinguish fires; liven up trampoline plants
Snowboard	- used on snow and ice floorings; can damage enemies by jumping on them
Stone Spear	- melee weapon; jump and press UP to log platforms to latch on them
Umbrella	- hold jump button on midair to glide down; protects player from water drops
		- keep hold jump button over water surface to use it like a boat
Crystal Hammer	- melee weapon; key to Crystal Island; breaks stones
Surfboard	- used on water surfaces; can damage enemies by jumping on them
Boomerang	- projectile weapon; press UP to throw upwards
Skateboard	- move faster on ground; can damage enemies by jumping on them
Stone Axe	- final weapon; bounces off rocks 

POWER (get these in mini-games)
P-coin		- raises attack power
J-coin		- makes player jump higher
D-coin		- enables dash; hold down B-button while running

SPECIAL ITEM (one time use; you can get it again in mini-games)
Heart		- restores 1 unit of health
Flask		- restores full health
Home Ticket	- warps player to house; a one-way ticket home
Warp Egg	- waprs you to the last pedestal where you lay it
Compass		- shows player location on map
Fairy		- revives player when KO'ed

------------
Field items:
------------
ENEMY DROPS
Fruits		- collect 8 to restore 1 unit of health
		- have at least 4 or more will make playing mini-games easier
Small Heart	- restores one unit of health
Star		- temporary invincibility

EGG CONTENTS
Meat		- restores full health
Small Heart	- restores one unit of health
Big Heart	- adds 1 max health point
Half Big Heart	- collect 2 pieces to complete 1 max health point

-----------
Mini-games:
-----------
Most of them you can play by repeatedly pressing B-button.
In the hurdles game, you need to press the A-button to jump while pressing B-button.
Others you need specific weapons to play.

-------------
Dino Friends:
-------------
As the intro shows, your Dinosaur friends were kidnapped by an evil-looking face. You save them by defeating island bosses.
You can bring one dino at a time; go to Dino Village and jump on them to ride. Select a weapon in the menu to swap them out.
Get hit once and they vanish. Get them back in Dino Village.

SPADE (RED RAPTOR)
Spew fireballs stronger than regular attacks and can destroy rocks
Can move in lava
Can still get damaged by fire enemies

HEART (BLUE RAPTOR)
Tail whip wave stronger than regular attacks and can destroy rocks
Does not slip on ice
Can still get damaged by ice enemies

CLUB (PINK PTERODACTYL)
Can fly on high places
Attacks by dropping stones 

DIAMOND (PURPLE PLESIOSAUR)
Slow on land, but fast in water
Attacks are stronger than regular attacks

STAR (GREEN TRICEROTOPS)
Does rolling jump attacks
Does not sink in quicksand

--------
Changes:
--------
Aside from English translation, here are other notable changes in the game:
ADV_ISLAND_IV(EN).ips
v1.0 (07/14/2018)
*The title screen is modified
*Fixed bonfire sprite
*Fixed a sprite inconsistency at the end

ADV_ISLAND_IV(EN)+.ips
v1.0 (07/14/2018)
*Changes made from ADV_ISLAND_IV(EN).ips
*Various palette changes to sprites and background
*Flask changed to Milk like previous games had
*Compass changed to Ring resembling first game
*Plant trampolines changed to Mushrooms
*Meat changed to Meat from third game

---------
ZIP file:
---------
1. This readme
2. ADV_ISLAND_IV(EN).ips
3. ADV_ISLAND_IV(EN)+.ips

----------------
ROM Information:
----------------
No-Intro Name: Takahashi Meijin no Bouken-jima IV (Japan)
(No-Intro version  20130731-235630)
File MD5:      DD53D022BB0B8D5A8D464690B14A0B30        
File SHA-1:    E73EFD3E932B9E3501CE9C77418BDBF0D59D75CD
File CRC32:    5ECFD3DC                                
ROM MD5:       17F974B2180DBC3247787CEDD4B82597        
ROM SHA-1:     60BA08558D5316686195F8F0B9765B4EE8B4543A
ROM CRC32:     7BD8F902                                

--------
Credits:
--------
Zynk Oxhyde - Full Hacking & Translation

----------
Utilities:
----------
WindHex hex editor by Bongo`
YY-CHR ROM graphics editor by YY
FCEUX 2.2.2 NES emulator debuggers

---------------
Special Thanks:
---------------
Romhacking.net - for hosting the patch
SpiderDave - for finding titlescreen palette

--------
Contact:
--------
Email: zynkoxhyde@yahoo.com

----------------------------
Disclaimer and Terms of Use:
----------------------------
* Zynk Oxhyde is not related or affiliated with Nintendo and the publisher of the original game.
* Do not sell this patch and the contents with it.
* Do not sell the pre-patched ROM into reproduction cartridges.
* You may distribute or host this patch provided that all files that come with it are intact.