GUN-NAC
Hacked by Zynk Oxhyde
2017

--------------
Date Released:
--------------
v1.0 February 15, 2017

------------
Description:
------------
This is an English translation of "Gun-Nac" for the NES. 
The difference between the US version from the JP version 
is that the former removed some portion of the intro and 
ending scenes featuring the heroine/mage/pilot. And the
boss that look like a human fetus was replaced with some
other alien thing.

---------------
Game Mechanics:
---------------
The game basically plays like any vertical shooter game on the NES.

* Controls:
  A = Shoot
  B = Bomb
  D-pad = Move
  Start = Pause
  Select = Change speed movement

--------
Weapons:
--------
1 - Default weapon. Upgraded, the ship shoots bullets in front of it in 3 different directions.
  - When Wing is equipped, the ship can shoot in 4 different directions upfront and 1 front behind, totalling of 5 directions.

2 - Energy ball. A large ball of energy that also discharges horizontal bullets from its side. 
  - When Wing is equipped, the ball becomes larger and powerful.

3 - Homing boomerangs. Upgraded, the ship shoots bullets in front of it in 3 different directions.
  - When Wing is equipped, the ship can shoot in 6 different directions.

4 - Flame thrower. Even when not pressing the fire button, the fire on the ship's nozzle can still damage enemies. 
    Shooting will stretch the flame. Upgraded, the flame becomes longer.
  - When Wing is equipped, the ship gets 2 gun assists from both sides, totalling of 3 flame throwers.

5 - Laser beams. the ship shoots 2 beams upfront. Upgraded, the ship shoots 3 beams shot upfront.
  - When Wing is equipped, the ship shoots out additional 4 beams, totalling of 6 beams shot with considerable distance from each other.

------
Bombs:	
------
* The player can have 4 bombs in the start of a stage. 
* The player can have up to 20 bombs.
* When shot down and has less than 4 bombs, the player will start with 4 bombs.
* When the player picks up a bomb with the same bomb that is in use, the bomb will have have a wider area of attack, but will consume 2 bomb count.
* The bombs can also destroy enemy projectiles.
* When bombs are deployed, the ship reverts to default bullets until the bomb expires.
* There are 4 types of bombs:
  F - "FIRE". A ring of fire orbs spin on a spot where it is deployed.

  B - "BLIZZARD". A vertical line that moves from left to right.

  T - "THUNDER". A wild lightning bolt that bounces off the screen.

  W - "WATER". A downpour of water drops from above like rain.


------------
Other Items:
------------
P - This item increases the weapon level.
Round Guys - shoot them to get either a weapons, bombs, or money. They just escape when touched.
Money bag - seems to have random sum of money used in shops.
Glowing Bomb - destroy all enemies on screen.


--------
Changes:
--------
v1.0 (02/15/2017) - initial release
Aside from translating the game into English, there are other things that are edited:
* the ending graphics text translated (the g'old lady and the girl trio)
* stage titles
* flipped over money bag to show $ sign

v1.1 (02/16/2017)
* Edited the mage's "Huh?" bubble (missed that one :P)

---------
ZIP file:
---------
1. This readme
2. GUNNAC(EN).ips


----------------
ROM Information:
----------------
File:   Gun-Nac (J).nes
Length: 262160 Bytes (2 Mbit)
CRC32:  F39B41A4
MD5:    029DAA68 8D2C51A2 96EB4E7F ED953D0D
SHA1:   48CE296D 9DDB59AB F13CECCD E777A3E4 3C27FF61


--------
Credits:
--------
Zynk Oxhyde - Hacking & Translation
Jonny2x4 - Translation from The Video Game Museum


----------
Utilities:
----------
WindHex hex editor by Bongo`
YY-CHR ROM graphics editor by YY
FCEUX 2.2.2 NES emulator debuggers


---------------
Special Thanks:
---------------
Romhacking.net - for hosting the patch
The Video Game Museum (http://www.vgmuseum.com) - for the endings and translations


--------
Contact:
--------
Email: zynkoxhyde@yahoo.com


-----------
Disclaimer:
-----------
Zynk Oxhyde is not related/affiliated with Nintendo, Tonkin House & Compile in any way.
Tonkin House & Compile owns this game & characters all rights reserved.
This patch is not for profit! This patch is free! Don't distribute this in pre-patched ROMs!
Don't ask Zynk Oxhyde for ROMs. Get your ROMs from anyhow you like.
Selling of reproduction cartridges with the patch applied is illegal! Zynk Oxhyde is against piracy!