Ultraman: Great Kaijuu Battle FC Translation

Contents:

1. Foreword.
2. Game description
3. Translation/hacking notes
4. Disclaimer
5. Staff 
===========================


1. Foreword

Hey everyone!
We're proud to present to you a new translation patch, for a little game called Ultraman: Kaijuu Daikessen, or Great Kaijuu Battle. Ultraman is an extremely popular franchise in Japan, spanning many different incarnations, featuring hundreds of characters, and overall being somewhat of a phenomenon out there. We decided to translate the game, as it's somewhat nostalgic to us, and it doesn't have that much text all things considered. Hope you have fun with it!


2. Game description

This game is basically a pretty simple platformer, typical of the NES era. You walk generally right/up and beat up various bad guys from the Ultraman franchise. You can also use sub-weapons and switch between them at will. Every once in a while you get a balloon popping minigame where you can win various prizes. Overall, it's a pretty simple game, but we liked it enough to give it a translation treatment.  One thing to keep in mind, though, is that several of the Ultramen look VERY similar, with the only real differences in their artwork being around the shoulder area. This can cause a bit of confusion as to who is speaking. Just remember that after beating a boss, Ultraman Zoffy speaks to your Ultraman, your Ultraman isn't talking to himself!


3. Translation notes

Ultraman: Great Kaijuu Battle has a rather simple story; you need to save the Ultra planet, as one day the Flame of Justice suddenly disappeared. It is up to you - the original Ultraman - to fix this mess. The main challenge were the planet names in-between various stages, mostly from the hacking perspective - they're all mentioned in the dialogue proper though, so that shouldn't be an issue. 


4. Hacking notes

After working out how text is formatted in this game, hacking it was fairly straight-forward, although the script had to be trimmed down to fit into the available space. The planet names in-between stages have proven difficult, though, so they have been left untranslated for the time being.


5. Disclaimer

This translation is a non-commercial and unofficial project which is in no way affiliated with the game creators or distributors. We don't own anything here and have no copyrights.
We release this translation in the form of a patch, not the actual patched disks. Please, don't ask us to send you the ROM, or where you can find it - we can't help you with that.

You can redistribute this translation freely as long as you don't ask money for it and include this readme.txt file with it. We don't condone any form of commercial redistribution. Please, keep that in mind.


6. Staff and special thanks

Eric Engel - hacking/testing/script editing
Cccmar - main translation

