KITERETSU ENCYCLOPEDIA
Hacked by Zynk Oxhyde
2016

--------------
Date Released:
--------------
v1.0 February 15, 2016

------------
Description:
------------
This is an English translation of "Kiteretsu Daihyakka" for the NES. The game is based on an anime of the same title.

------
Story:
------
Kiteretsu made a Dream World traveling machine, the Dream Mirror. But it went haywire and scattered Kiteretsu and his friends in Dream World.
Its up to Kiteretsu to save them and go back home.

---------------
Game Mechanics:
---------------
The game is a action platformer. The game has 5 stages.
*Controls:
A = Jump; Swim in water; Confirm button; Hit blocks like Mario; Jump on enemies will kill them (50% accuracy)
B = Use item. Hold B+Left/Right will make you dash
Left/Right = Move
Up/down = Move cursor menu; Press UP on ceilings to walk upside down, Press DOWN to walk rightside up
Down = Crouch, you can move Left/Right while crouching; press on books to enter the Laboratory; press on TVs, telephones, and even 1 tile blocks to read secret messages; press to go down elevator platforms
Start = Pause
Select = Calls your friend back to where you are standing

------------
Field Items:
------------
gold coins=1 gold point
red goins=5 gold poins
heart=1 health point

-----------
Inventions:
-----------
Hell-Pass	  = IMPORTANT! Needed to complete the game. Grants a retry but you still need sufficient amount of gold and health to trigger it
Shrink-Ray 	  = makes enemies small
Oxygen-Cream 	  = needed when entering water stages
Treasure-Finder   = reveals a trove of gold coins in place blocks, found only in water stages
Psychokinesis-Hat = lift stones
Earth-Shaker 	  = creates mild earhquakes
Walkthrough-Walls = makes you walk through specific wall blocks
SuperTengu 	  = makes you temporarily invincible
KyojinGan 	  = not sure... maybe makes you invulnerable once you touch an enemy for a few seconds?

----------
Passwords:
----------
Found after completing a stage. But you need to invent the Hell-Pass (aka Kiteretsu Hell) first.

Here's a BONUS! Below is the password that makes you invincible. However, you need to avoid the hearts or fall into pits or else, the effect will wear off:

jcaaaaaa

--------
Changes:
--------
v1.0 (02/15/2016) - initial release
Aside from translating the game into English, there are other things that are edited:
* A spiffy title screen

---------
ZIP file:
---------
1. This readme
2. KITERETSU(EN).ips

----------------
ROM Information:
----------------
File:   Kiteretsu Dai Hyakka (Japan).nes
Length: 262160 Bytes (2 Mbit)
CRC32:  B6F4B759
MD5:    9EE8A97D E78792B0 95646C26 D1D110AE
SHA1:   417A3B9E 76223138 8295DFE3 5577C240 46334324

--------
Credits:
--------
Zynk Oxhyde - Full Hacking and Translation

----------
Utilities:
----------
WindHex hex editor by Bongo`
YY-CHR ROM graphics editor by YY
FCEUX NES emulator debuggers

---------------
Special Thanks:
---------------
Romhacking.net - for hosting the patch

--------
Contact:
--------
Email: zynkoxhyde@yahoo.com

-----------
Disclaimer:
-----------
Zynk Oxhyde is not related/affiliated with Nintendo or Epoch in any way.
Epoch/Fujiko F. Fujio owns this game & characters all rights reserved.
This patch is not for profit! This patch is free! Don't distribute this in pre-patched ROMs!
Don't ask Zynk Oxhyde for ROMs. Get your ROMs from anyhow you like.