BRAVE FIGHTER OF THE SUN: FIGHBIRD GB
Hacked by Zynk Oxhyde
2016

--------------
Date Released:
--------------
v1.0 May 23, 2016

------------
Description:
------------
This is an English translation of "Taiyou no Yuusha: Fighbird GB" for the Nintendo Game Boy.

------
Story:
------
From Wikipedia :P
In 2010, an evil energy being called Draias comes flying to the earth. It co-operates with Jango, a wicked scientist, 
in secret to bring ruin to the world. Upon its arrival, the Space Police Force put their spirits into special android 
machines built by Doctor Amano that have transformable bodies. Fighbird enters one such android and lives as the human 
Yutaro Katori. He transforms into the super robot Fighbird when the enemy attacks.

---------------
Game Mechanics:
---------------
A = switch weapons; you get a total of 3 special weapons (charged only)
B = shoot; hold B to charge your attacks, varies with charged levels
Start = pause
Directional button = move

------
Items:
------
? = this has different effects in each stage: destroys all enemies or freezes them a few seconds, or makes you fast or slow
Any other icons = either adds a special weapon and/or heals you; if you don't get shot down, you keep your upgrades

--------
Changes:
--------
v1.0 (05/23/2016) - initial release
Aside from translating the game into English, there are other things that are edited:
* A spiffy title screen
* That tiny "FIGHBIRD" logo

---------
ZIP file:
---------
1. This readme
2. FIGHBIRD-GB(EN).ips

----------------
ROM Information:
----------------
File:   Taiyou no Yuusha - Firebird GB (J).gb
Length: 131072 Bytes (1 Mbit)
CRC32:  4DAFB6A9
MD5:    5F95D1C9 F89A8F3E CCDCE22C 2E0A9329
SHA1:   2C849977 8B677B03 AACB0B5F CBA06021 DBBBAFCA

--------
Credits:
--------
Zynk Oxhyde - Full Hacking and Translation

----------
Utilities:
----------
BRB Gameboy emulator & debugger by Bas Steendijk
WindHex hex editor by Bongo`
YY-CHR ROM graphics editor by YY

---------------
Special Thanks:
---------------
Romhacking.net - for hosting the patch

--------
Contact:
--------
Email: zynkoxhyde@yahoo.com

-----------
Disclaimer:
-----------
Zynk Oxhyde is not related/affiliated with Nintendo or Irem in any way.
Irem/Sunrise owns this game & characters all rights reserved.
This patch is not for profit! This patch is free! Don't distribute this in pre-patched ROMs!
Don't ask Zynk Oxhyde for ROMs. Get your ROMs from anyhow you like.